<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-15T09:50:12-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dylan Herts</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">J.P. Lick’s – September 9, 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/09/09/jplicks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="J.P. Lick's -- September 9, 2019" /><published>2019-09-09T08:58:45-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-09T08:58:45-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/09/09/jplicks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/09/09/jplicks.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;jp-licks-september-9-2019&quot;&gt;J.P. Lick’s, September 9, 2019&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had spent the afternoon wandering down Newbury Street. I stopped in the quiet little J.P. Lick’s location on Charles Street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-tasted&quot;&gt;What I Tasted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butter Almond; Cappuccino Crunch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-ordered&quot;&gt;What I Ordered&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butter Almond is creamy and delicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The base is definitely a butter flavor, not simply cream or vanilla. It’s quite sweet, which isn’t surprising for a cream flavor like this one (or, for example, maple walnut or butter pecan), but I found it a little too sweet. Others could reasonably disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whole, raw almonds added some crunch. They provided some nice variation, but they should have been roasted to make them less bitter and more crunchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The texture was soft, almost too soft by New England standards. It was easy to spoon but melted quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-shop&quot;&gt;The Shop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any other town, J.P. Lick’s would be a standout. They experiment with seasonal flavors and consistently nail some of their more traditional ones, see, e.g., black raspberry. But in a town with so many great options, it’s hard to forgive some of Lick’s shortcomings: their texture can be hit-or-miss, their execution sometimes falls short, as the raw almonds did here, and they cost at least as much as their smaller-batch competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, Lick’s is popular and for good reason. They have locations all over Boston. And their ice cream is, overall, rather good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J.P. Lick’s is the baseline for ice cream in Boston. That isn’t to say that it’s a bad scoop shop–just that it’s a good one in a town full of greats.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">J.P. Lick’s, September 9, 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Il Massimo del Gelato – August 17, 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/08/17/ilmassimo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Il Massimo del Gelato -- August 17, 2019" /><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/08/17/ilmassimo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/08/17/ilmassimo.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;il-massimo-del-gelato-august-17-2019&quot;&gt;Il Massimo del Gelato, August 17, 2019&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of our honeymoon, my wife and I had one final day in Milan. The city had emptied out for the summer, and most businesses were closed. She loves gelato, especially chocolate, and so given the shortage of activities, she looked for Milan’s best. She found Il Massimo. Thankfully, it was open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-tasted&quot;&gt;What I Tasted&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Il Massimo is known for its various flavors of chocolate. I counted at least seven. We tried as many as we could: 70% dark chocolate, spicy chocolate, chocolate with cherry, with rum, and with orange and Grand Marnier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 70% dark and the orange and Grand Marnier were the best. The rum flavor was strangely watery, and the spicy chocolate flavor was too hot, even for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-ordered&quot;&gt;What I Ordered&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooked by a sample, I chose the 70% dark chocolate. And while I rarely spring for a second flavor, I added pistachio, which is my first-choice among gelato flavors. The 70% dark chocolate stood up to further scrutiny: rich and smooth, it was probably the best chocolate gelato I’ve ever had. The pistachio was excellent, too, but not quite as good. Both melted slowly as we sat on the curb of a quiet Milanese side-street and watched a cab driver run in for a cone–a further sign that we were in the right spot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Il Massimo del Gelato, August 17, 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Toscanini’s – July 25, 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/07/25/toscis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Toscanini's -- July 25, 2019" /><published>2019-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/07/25/toscis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/icecream/2019/07/25/toscis.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;toscaninis-july-25-2019&quot;&gt;Toscanini’s, July 25, 2019&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An errand tore me away from my bar studies. Afterwards, my walk home took me under sunny skies and past Toscanini’s, so how could I resist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-tasted&quot;&gt;What I Tasted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cajeta (goat milk caramel); Chocolate Black Pepper Bourbon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-ordered&quot;&gt;What I Ordered&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chocolate Black Pepper Bourbon is named by order of appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the chocolate–moderately dark, maybe around 55%. It’s dark enough to announce itself, but still a little sweet. Next, the black pepper. It’s light but it’s there: a tickle at the back of the throat, a crackle on the tongue. Finally, there’s barely a flash of bourbon syrup at the end. Together, the flavor is a nice rich-chocolate variation, and the chocolate/pepper combo will likely appeal to those who like spicy-chocolate flavors, &lt;em&gt;see, e.g.&lt;/em&gt;, Jeni’s Queen City Cayenne. As for the bourbon: I say turn it up or take it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I would expect of Tosci’s, the texture was nearly perfect: thick enough to bend a plastic spoon. I say nearly because there was one tiny streak of ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-shop&quot;&gt;The Shop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scoop is a great example of what makes Toscanini my favorite in Boston: high-quality ice cream in an inventive, well-executed flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Toscanini’s, July 25, 2019</summary></entry></feed>